SCOTT M. BATES

20250 South Cliffside Lane, Beavercreek, Oregon 97004 503.789.3694 scottb@bctonline.com

SUMMARY

Director, engineer, and IT professional with 25+ year's progressive experience. Expertise in managing, team development, and restructuring organizations, hiring, covering multi-state territories, providing 24x7 remote and on-site support, and most recently non-profit charity management. Demonstrated high-level administration skills of scheduling, prioritizing, budgeting and asset tracking. Specializing in documentation issues. Regarded for identifying opportunities and solving problems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PREGNANCY CARE CENTERS OF NWV Molalla, Ca	anby, & Woodburn, OR 2008 – 2010)
Executive Director	2008 - 2010)
Board Consultant	2008	

Directed non-profit 501(c)(3) organization with a \$200K budget and three satellite offices providing counseling services to the community. Cut expenses 42% during first year in position. Created administration office. Implemented several new internal and donor facing programs.

PRACTICAL COMPUTING SOLUTIONS Beavercreek, OR

2006 - 2008

Operated a private computer repair firm specializing in small to medium sized businesses. Provided custom built computer systems as well as data security and backup solutions. Registered Microsoft, Dell and SonicWall solutions provider.

INTEL CORPORATION Hillsboro, Oregon	2000 – 2006
Technical Marketing Engineer	2005 - 2006
Technical Support Engineer	2000 - 2005
Customer Support Engineer, CDI Corp.	2000

Functioned as engineer, liaison and mentor through various positions. Authored technical manuals and online training, coordinated support efforts, provided staff and development planning. Coordinated the seed unit program and was a liaison between engineering and customer/product development teams. Developed workaround for a process gap in procedures that recovered \$180,000 worth of missing equipment. Received twenty-seven Customer Heros, six Kudos awards, two Be Excellent awards, one ICS departmental worldwide award, and one Divisional Recognition Award. I routinely had satisfaction ratings in the high nineties.

Scott M. Bates Page 2of 2

NORDSTROM, INC. Seattle, Washington	1991 - 1999
Systems Engineer	1998 - 1999
Information Services Technician	1994 - 1998
Data Services Technician	1991 - 1993

Provided support and on-site maintenance of all electronic data and voice processing equipment. Worked as part of a team to develop a comprehensive in-house maintenance program that employed the most cost-effective combination of OEM agreements, third party, and self-maintenance. Saved \$3.3M by proposing, developing and implementing in-house support of 250 large kVA UPS systems avoiding \$20,000/unit upgrades. Reengineered vendor's PCB design to correct factory flaw saving \$1.4M. Successfully absorbed all configuration, upgrade and maintenance duties on PBX level switches resulting in annual savings of \$150K/year.

MEIER & FRANK COMPANY Portland, Oregon	1984 - 1991
Data Communications Engineer	1989 - 1991
Field Service Engineer	1986 - 1989
Entry Level Field Technician	1984 - 1986

Provided 24-hour on-call maintenance, repair and modification of all company owned electronic equipment. This included troubleshooting complex systems to the component level. Selected to lead team of 30 technicians through a difficult reorganization involving an 80% reduction in force without decreasing workload. Received the May Company "Outstanding Achievement" award for converting 800 point of sale systems from a proprietary to open system platform. Facilitated the migration of Portland, Oregon data center to Los Angeles, California with a minimum of downtime. This included 500 users at 7 sites.

EDUCATION, CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

- **INTERNAL COMPANY TRAINING:** Completed over 60 business related, personal development, and product related trainings.
- EXTERNAL TRAINING: Carenet (certified director), NIFLA (linear services model), MI Foundation (engaging champions, grant writing, donor databases, banquets), Linfield College (business major), ITT Technical Institute (electronic design and troubleshooting), New Horizons, & Infotec (Microsoft MCSE, Novell CNE, and Linux courses), Avery/Soabar (thermal barcode ticket printer certification of proficiency), Sensormatic Electronics (RF security system certificate of qualification), Hewlett Packard (data communications troubleshooting techniques).
- STATE OF OREGON Limited Energy License: Extensive experience in the design, installation, terminating, documenting, and the general control of building data wiring. Former cabling contractor, member of BICSI, consulted on State of Oregon Notification Center move to new building.